<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:base="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/ongoing.atom" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>ongoing</title>
    <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/</id>
    <link href="./"/>
    <link rel="self" href=""/>
    <logo>rsslogo.jpg</logo>
    <icon>/favicon.ico</icon>
    <updated>2006-01-24T07:32:22-08:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Tim Bray</name>
    </author>
    <subtitle>ongoing fragmented essay by Tim Bray</subtitle>
    <rights>All content written by Tim Bray and photos by Tim Bray Copyright Tim Bray, some rights reserved, see /ongoing/misc/Copyright</rights>
    <generator uri="/misc/Colophon">Generated from XML source code using Perl, Expat, XML::Parser, Emacs, Mysql, and ImageMagick. Industrial strength technology, baby.</generator>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/24/NBExtras">
        <title>nbextras.org</title>
        <link href="NBExtras"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/24/NBExtras</id>
        <published>2006-01-24T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-24T07:32:19-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology/Java"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Java"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology/Publishing"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Publishing"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>I ran across a couple of blog pointers to 
                    <a href="http://www.nbextras.org/">nbextras.org</a> and thought it looked kind of cool and kind of useful and kind of lightweight, and I wondered how it came to be here this week when it wasn’t there last week. So I chatted with Trung Duc Tran (he’s one of the senior people over in our Prague NetBeans shop) who put it together with a couple of other co-conspirators and asked “How’d you do that?” Well, it turns out that they found a cheap hosting service and rented a fake 
                    <a href="http://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/Research/SRG/netos/xen/">Xen</a>-based server and cobbled together the 
                    <a href="http://jetty.mortbay.org/jetty/">Jetty</a> server and the 
                    <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/pebble">Pebble</a> blogging engine. “It’s amazing”, Trung told me, “how much work you can get a servlet engine to do when you have all the data in memory.” I asked whether it was a lot of development time and he seemed surprised, they’d discussed it over lunch one day last week and set it up over the weekend and now it’s up. This Java/Web/Open-Source technology, it’s gonna catch on, you just watch.
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/23/Election-Day">
        <title>Election Day</title>
        <link href="Election-Day"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/23/Election-Day</id>
        <published>2006-01-23T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-23T17:17:08-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World/Politics"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Politics"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World/Places/Canada"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Places"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Canada"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>I voted early this morning; we’ve been living in this neighborhood long enough that I recognized some people over at the poll, hung out and chatted for a bit. It felt good. I think that what’s happening today here in Canada highlights the single essential thing about democracy; I 
                    <a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2003/02/23/Democracy">wrote about this almost three years ago</a>, but it’s worth saying again: I don’t particularly trust “the people” to pick the right policies or even to pick the right leaders. I do, however trust them to detect the condition that the government has been bad and needs to be turfed. Which we, today, are apparently the process of doing. Frankly, I think it would be OK to pick the next government by random selection, and we probably wouldn’t do that much worse than the current electoral crap-shoot. The important thing—
                    <em>the only thing that really matters</em>—is that we retain the right to throw ’em out in a peaceful and orderly fashion, at our sole discretion and for any reason. There are a lot of people in the world without that right. It’s the one that all the others flow from.
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/23/BWV-131">
        <title>5✭♫: BWV 131</title>
        <link href="BWV-131"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/23/BWV-131</id>
        <published>2006-01-23T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-23T10:21:53-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts/Music/Recordings"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Music"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Recordings"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts/Music/5 Stars"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="5 Stars"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I think I should start with 
                <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J.S._Bach">J.S. Bach</a>, since we have a special relationship. BWV 131 is one of his cantatas, based on 
                <i>Aus der Tiefen rufe ich, Herr, zu dir</i> (from Psalm 130), composed in 1707, and if you buy it you’ll like it. 
                <i>(“5✭♫” series introduction 
                    <a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/23/5-Star-Music">here</a>; with 
                    <a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/23/5-Star-Music#p-1">an explanation</a> of why the title may look broken.)
                </i>
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>I think I should start with 
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J.S._Bach">J.S. Bach</a>, since we have a special relationship. BWV 131 is one of his cantatas, based on 
                    <i>Aus der Tiefen rufe ich, Herr, zu dir</i> (from Psalm 130), composed in 1707, and if you buy it you’ll like it. 
                    <i>(“5✭♫” series introduction 
                        <a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/23/5-Star-Music">here</a>; with 
                        <a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/23/5-Star-Music#p-1">an explanation</a> of why the title may look broken.)
                    </i>
                </p>
                <p>That “special relationship” is, first of all, just because I really like a lot of Bach’s music, and second, because I was a student of the cello for some years, and all cellists perforce get a lot of hands-on time with old Sebastian.</p>
                <h2 id="p-3">BWV</h2>
                <p>Some of Bach’s works have been lost but over a thousand remain, and the 
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BWV">BWV</a> numbers are used to keep track of them. They are assigned thematically not chronologically; it so happens that the cantatas come first in the sequence, BWV 1-224.
                </p>
                <h2 id="p-4">Context</h2>
                <p>For much of his adult life, Bach’s employment required him to provide music for each week’s divine worship, some proportion of it being new on any given Sunday. This usually took the form of a 
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cantata">cantata</a>, with a handful of movements lasting less than a half-hour. We citizens of earth owe the eighteenth-century Lutheran church our thanks for these onerous terms of employment, because many of 
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_cantatas_by_Johann_Sebastian_Bach">the 200 or so cantatas</a> written for this purpose are extremely good.
                </p>
                <p>BWV 131 is among the earliest—maybe the earliest—of the known cantatas, written while Bach was in his early twenties.</p>
                <h2 id="p-2">The Music</h2>
                <p>The melody is passed back and forth among the woodwinds, bass and tenor soloists, and the choir. I gave five stars to the middle three of the five movements; each of which features a well-sung solo part with the choir’s lines behind either rising slowly like an upwelling of joy, or drifting down like ten thousand silver feathers through twilit air.</p>
                <h2 id="p-1">How to Sample It</h2>
                <p>It turns out that there’s an excellent 
                    <a href="http://www.bach-cantatas.com/">Bach Cantatas Website</a>, which I only discovered in researching this piece; it seems remarkably complete. The 
                    <a href="http://www.bach-cantatas.com/BWV131.htm">coverage of BWV 131</a> includes 
                    <a href="http://www.bach-cantatas.com/Mus/BWV131-Mus.htm">downloadable music</a>; the m4u didn’t work for me and the RealAudio is only 32k/sec, hardly high fidelity, but you can get the idea.
                </p>
                <img class="inline" src="Herreweghe-Kantaten.jpg" alt="J.S. Bach, Cantatas 131, 73, and 105, featuring Philippe Herreweghe and the Collegium Vocale of Ghent"/>
                <h2 id="p-5">Getting It</h2>
                <p>The Cantata site also lists a huge number of recordings; the one I have is from 1992, by Philippe Herreweghe and the Collegium Vocale of Ghent, Virgin Classics 0 7777 59237 2 8; just now Amazon 
                    <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00000DNWA/002-9351053-7203258?n=5174">says it’s out of print</a> (while offering samples), but I totally recommend it if you can find it; among other things, it includes 
                    <a href="http://www.bach-cantatas.com/BWV105.htm">BWV 105</a>, whose third movement also got five stars. Hmm, if they’re declining to sell the music, why shouldn’t I be able to post it? But I digress. An Amazon search for “Herreweghe 131” yields a few other options.
                </p>
                <p>Here’s the great thing about Bach: his music is really hard to screw up. Most of his works are available in a bunch of different recordings, all selling well because they’re good. So if you visit your favourite shiny-disc emporium and buy something that’s advertised as having BWV 131 on it, you’ll probably be happy with what you take home.</p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/23/5-Star-Music">
        <title>5 ✭ ♫ Mondays</title>
        <link href="5-Star-Music"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/23/5-Star-Music</id>
        <published>2006-01-23T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-23T10:21:44-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts/Music/Recordings"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Music"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Recordings"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts/Music/5 Stars"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="5 Stars"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The idea 
                <a href="http://jwz.livejournal.com/578440.html">came from JWZ</a> in late 2005: why not rate all the music in your jukebox? If your jukebox is iTunes, you create an “unrated” smart-playlist containing all the tunes with no stars, then you set up the Party Shuffle to draw from it, then you rate them as they go by except when you’re not listening, and after a few months, you have them all rated. I haven’t got them all rated, but I have quite a few labeled ✭✭✭✭✭, which means “a tune that in some way gives me as much pleasure as music can.” I care a lot about (and am reasonably literate about) music, so I decided I to share some of this five-star stuff with the world. I’ll try to post something most Mondays. 
                <i>[Does the title look broken? 
                    <a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/23/5-Star-Music#p-1">Here’s why.</a>]
                </i>
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>The idea 
                    <a href="http://jwz.livejournal.com/578440.html">came from JWZ</a> in late 2005: why not rate all the music in your jukebox? If your jukebox is iTunes, you create an “unrated” smart-playlist containing all the tunes with no stars, then you set up the Party Shuffle to draw from it, then you rate them as they go by except when you’re not listening, and after a few months, you have them all rated. I haven’t got them all rated, but I have quite a few labeled ✭✭✭✭✭, which means “a tune that in some way gives me as much pleasure as music can.” I care a lot about (and am reasonably literate about) music, so I decided I to share some of this five-star stuff with the world. I’ll try to post something most Mondays. 
                    <i>[Does the title look broken? 
                        <a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/23/5-Star-Music#p-1">Here’s why.</a>]
                    </i>
                </p>
                <img src="Five-Star-Mondays.png" class="inline" alt="How the title should look"/>
                <h2 id="p-1">Title Broken?</h2>
                <p>The title is supposed to look something like this picture. It works fine on all the Mac browsers I’ve tried, on most recent Linuxes, and on Windows if you’re using Firefox. I’m told that on most versions of Windows, it’s broken in IE. I’m not going to fix it here, because it’s correct and I like the way it looks. Get a better browser.</p>
                <h2 id="p-2">Old, But Good</h2>
                <p>A lot of the music I’ll describe is really old; as I progressed through my forties I managed to outgrow my angst at not being hip and up-to-the-minute in my tastes; I do manage to fall in love with the occasional current hit, but no longer worry about a lot of my faves being from 1977 or 1866 or 1755. Having said that, there are a few 21st-century cuts here, and I hope the number grows. </p>
                <h2 id="p-3">Covering the Waterfront</h2>
                <p>The music on my computer is a tiny and random sliver of the music on my shelves, selected by impulse-grabbing random disks. Plus there’s a selection of real obscurities dating from the golden days of Napster — all of which I have in some other medium or would buy given an opportunity. So, the music has no common thread; but some songs come with stories.</p>
                <p>My tastes are broad rather than deep; while I listen to more 
                    <em>kinds</em> of music than anyone I know, I’m not an 
                    <em>authority</em> on Fifties 
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hard_bop">hard-bop</a> or 
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trip_hop">Bristol Trip-Hop</a> or the 
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Second_Viennese_School">Vienna School</a> or any of the others. Except maybe for J.S. Bach, with whom I have a special relationship; but this will 
                    <em>not</em> be all-classical; I will cover most genres, excepting 
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operetta">operetta</a> and hip-hop.
                </p>
                <h2 id="p-4">Try, Then Buy (On Disk, Please)</h2>
                <p>So the idea is, most Mondays, to introduce some music that maybe you don’t know about, and to avoid both wilful obscurity and greatest-hits pandering. Many weeks I’ll recommend a single song, but I’ll also do aggregations (albums, compositions, micro-genres) which have multiple 5-✭ members.</p>
                <p>The following will sound like bragging, but: I’ve noticed over the years that when I’ve told someone “Listen to this, you’ll like it”, most times they do. I’ll provide pointers to help track down online versions of the music for sampling purposes. If you like what you hear, please go buy it on an uncompressed, un-rights-restricted Compact Disc, then it’ll be yours for the long term. Good music deserves nothing less.</p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/22/Washington-Post-Goof">
        <title>Washington Post Screws Up</title>
        <link href="Washington-Post-Goof"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/22/Washington-Post-Goof</id>
        <published>2006-01-22T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-22T14:23:36-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World/Journalism"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Journalism"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology/Internet"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Internet"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>The Washington Post has noticed the brewing storm over the two-tier Internet; 
                    <a href="http://doc.weblogs.com/">Doc Searls</a> gets the long-term credit for 
                    <a href="http://www.linuxjournal.com/article/8673">starting the storm brewing</a>. The WaPo piece, 
                    <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2006/01/21/AR2006012100094.html">The Coming Tug of War Over the Internet</a>, is clueless, at a trivial level in alleging that the debate is happening “on obscure blogs”, but most of all in the outrageous claim that “Companies like Google and Yahoo pay some fees to connect to their servers to the Internet, but AT&amp;T will collect little if any additional revenue when Yahoo starts offering new features that take up lots of bandwidth on the Internet. When Yahoo’s millions of customers download huge blocks of video or play complex video games, AT&amp;T ends up carrying that increased digital traffic without additional financial compensation.” While the details of the deals by which the big boys buy bandwidth are closely-guarded secrets, the notion that any of them can dramatically increase their net traffic without paying for it, that notion is just wacko. I’ve sent Christopher Stern, the author, an email, but this silliness is already on the streets of Washington in a few hundred thousand dead-tree instances. The difference between blogs and the mainstream media is that when we screw up, we can mostly repair the damage.
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2004/12/12/BMS">
        <title>Statistics</title>
        <link href="BMS"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2004/12/12/BMS</id>
        <published>2004-12-12T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-22T10:37:22-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology/Publishing"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Publishing"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology/Web"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Web"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Almost every Sunday I grab the week’s 
                <span class="o">ongoing</span> logfiles and update my numbers. I find it interesting and maybe others will too, so this entry is now the charts’ permanent home. I’ll update it most weeks, probably. 
                <i>[Updated: 2006/01/22.]</i>
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>Almost every Sunday I grab the week’s 
                    <span class="o">ongoing</span> logfiles and update my numbers. I find it interesting and maybe others will too, so this entry is now the charts’ permanent home. I’ll update it most weeks, probably. 
                    <i>[Updated: 2006/01/22.]</i>
                </p>
                <img src="Browser-Market-Share.png" alt="Browser market shares at ‘ongoing’"/>
                <div class="caption">
                    <p>Browsers visiting 
                        <span class="o">ongoing</span>, percent.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <img src="Browsers-via-search.png" alt="Browser market shares at ‘ongoing’, visitors via search engines"/>
                <div class="caption">
                    <p>Browsers visiting 
                        <span class="o">ongoing</span> via search engines, percent.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <img src="Search-Engines.png" alt="Search engine market shares at ‘ongoing’"/>
                <div class="caption">
                    <p>Search referrals to 
                        <span class="o">ongoing</span>.
                    </p>
                </div>
                <img src="Feeds.png" alt="Rss and Atom feed fetches"/>
                <div class="caption">
                    <p>Fetches of the RSS 2.0 and Atom 1.0 feeds.</p>
                </div>
                <p>The notes on usage and source code will return in coming weeks when I get the cycles to rewrite this whole article.</p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/20/Glassfish-Aquarium">
        <title>The Aquarium</title>
        <link href="Glassfish-Aquarium"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/20/Glassfish-Aquarium</id>
        <published>2006-01-20T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-20T19:19:49-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology/Java"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Java"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology/Publishing"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Publishing"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology/Web/Services"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Web"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Services"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>People have been asking for it since forever, and recent releases of 
                    <a href="http://www.rollerweblogger.org/">Roller</a> now have a group-blogging feature. I’ve always been skeptical of the idea, which redefines “blog” from being about an individual voice to being about a shared interest; because people are bigger and more interesting than their interests. But over the last couple of weeks, my attention has several times been drawn to pieces in 
                    <a href="http://blogs.sun.com/roller/page/theaquarium">The Aquarium</a>, which is a group blog about 
                    <a href="http://java.sun.com/javaee/glassfish/">GlassFish</a>. While I’m not really an EE kinda guy, I can see how someone who cares about that stuff could find this kind of a resource useful. For example, check out 
                    <a href="http://blogs.sun.com/roller/page/theaquarium?entry=publishing_a_restful_web_service">this pointer</a> to an over-elaborated but nonetheless useful article about doing REST in in JAX. Maybe “group blogs” have legs.
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/20/FSS">
        <title>FSS: Feather, Gauze, Vase</title>
        <link href="FSS"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/20/FSS</id>
        <published>2006-01-20T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-20T19:07:09-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts/Photos"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Photos"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Friday Slide Scan #19 is from around 1990 and is well-described by this fragment’s title; it’s really very pretty.</div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>Friday Slide Scan #19 is from around 1990 and is well-described by this fragment’s title; it’s really very pretty.</p>
                <img src="1034.png" alt="Feather and vase through sheer curtain"/>
                <p>I’m pretty sure that vase was picked up at a craft fair, something I visited regularly in an earlier life, but now we have no room for more decorations.</p>
                <p>Images in the Friday Slide Scans are from 35mm slides taken between 1953 and 2003 by (in rough chronological order) 
                    <a href="http://www.textuality.com/BillBray/">Bill Bray</a>, 
                    <a href="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2004/08/11/MomsGarden">Jean Bray</a>, Tim Bray, Cath Bray, and 
                    <a href="http://www.laurenwood.org/anyway/">Lauren Wood</a>; when I know exactly who took one, I’ll say. Most but not all of the slides were on Kodachrome; they were digitized using a Nikon CoolScan 4000 ED scanner and cleaned up by a combination of the Nikon scanning software and PhotoShop Elements.
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/20/Marketing-Truth">
        <title>Marketing Truth</title>
        <link href="Marketing-Truth"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/20/Marketing-Truth</id>
        <published>2006-01-20T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-20T14:17:15-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Business/Marketing"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Business"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Marketing"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>I get peeved at 
                    <a href="http://www.nicholasgcarr.com/">Nicholas Carr</a> sometimes, but he’s done a superb piece of work pushing hard on 
                    <a href="http://www.roughtype.com/archives/2006/01/saps_truthstret.php">SAP</a> and 
                    <a href="http://www.roughtype.com/archives/2006/01/oracles_funny_n.php">Oracle</a> for using statistics in their ads in a way that is at best non-transparent and at worst, well let’s not go there. It’s got to the point that whenever I see a quantitative claim in an ad I assume it’s a lie. There should be penalties; public ridicule feels appropriate.
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/20/Java-One">
        <title>Upcoming Gig: JavaOne</title>
        <link href="Java-One"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/20/Java-One</id>
        <published>2006-01-20T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-20T12:59:46-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology/Java"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Java"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World/Tim Bray"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Tim Bray"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>Hah, I’m delighted. 
                    <a href="http://java.sun.com/javaone/sf/index.jsp">JavaOne</a> accepted my talk, entitled 
                    <cite>Sigrid: The simplest possible grid computing platform</cite>. See you in San Fran in May!
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/17/GPL3-Draft">
        <title>GPL3 Draft</title>
        <link href="GPL3-Draft"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/17/GPL3-Draft</id>
        <published>2006-01-17T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-19T13:28:23-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Business/Intellectual Property"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Business"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Intellectual Property"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>The GNU Public License is an important piece of our infrastructure these days, so I read 
                    <a href="http://blogs.sun.com/roller/page/webmink?entry=gpl_v3_released">Simon Phipps’ report</a> with interest, and decided I should give the 
                    <a href="http://gplv3.fsf.org/draft">V3 draft</a> a good close read. Unfortunately, while the text may be sensible, the HTML is an unreadable stinking heap of Plone dung; I attempted to print out a human-usable version and the results were unprintable. So I cleaned it up by hand, inserted a tiny bit of minimal styling to make it a bit more human readable, made sure it was validated, and here it is: 
                    <a href="http://www.tbray.org/gpl/gpl3-draft.html">GPL3 Draft of January 2006</a>. 
                    <i>[Update: On Simon Phipps’ suggestion, I equipped the draft with 
                        <a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2004/05/31/PurpleAgain">purple pilcrows</a>, so each paragraph has its own URL.
                    </i>]
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/19/Sunbeams">
        <title>Sunbeams: Fallen Eucalypt</title>
        <link href="Sunbeams"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/19/Sunbeams</id>
        <published>2006-01-19T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-19T11:05:22-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World/Life Online/Sun"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Life Online"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Sun"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>Back in 2004 when we were just getting blogging going at Sun, I had this 
                    <a href="/ongoing/What/The%20World/Life%20Online/Sun/">Sunbeams</a> series, where I highlighted interesting sunblog posts. Just now, I had a few browser tabs I was thinking of writing about, and noticed that four of them qualified, thus this revival. 
                    <i>Item:</i>
                    <a href="http://www.opensolaris.org/jive/thread.jspa?threadID=3788&amp;tstart=60">mod_dtrace</a>; there’ve been times I would have paid big money for something like this. 
                    <i>Item:</i>
                    <a href="http://blogs.sun.com/roller/page/robogeek?entry=corporate_it_security_at_sun">Neutering WinXP</a> to make it safe. 
                    <i>Item:</i>
                    <a href="http://blogs.sun.com/roller/page/timcaynes?entry=a_medley_of_sausage">a medley of sausage</a>. 
                    <i>Item:</i> JohnnyL 
                    <a href="http://blogs.sun.com/roller/page/johnnyl?entry=what_i_did_on_my">has a really bad day</a> (illustrated). Yow.
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/19/Good-Suit">
        <title>Surprising the Eye</title>
        <link href="Good-Suit"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/19/Good-Suit</id>
        <published>2006-01-19T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-19T00:26:18-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World/Puzzling Evidence"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Puzzling Evidence"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts/Photos"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Photos"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">What happened was, I was speaking at a conference, sharing the stage with the Chairman of the SEC (by video) and (in the flesh) the SEC’s CIO and the FDIC’s Deputy CIO. No pointers because it deserves serious coverage. For the occasion, I (obviously) wore my best custom-made Italian suit (grey) and an understated-but-strong tie (mostly blue), along with my dapper new 
                <a href="http://www.baileyhats.com/">Bailey’s</a> fedora. Then I took off for two heavy-geek meetings at Sun campuses and a visit to Technorati. When I pulled into the Sun parking lot, I thought about pulling the tie off and the jeans on but decided it would do ’em good to see a geek in a suit, and I have to say I got as many blank-faced 
                <em>WTF-is-this</em> looks as anyone could want. But then, at the end of all my meetings, while I was trudging down a 
                <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_of_Market_%28San_Francisco%29">SoMa</a> street to my alarmingly-huge Avis van ($20 in gas for a day going up &amp; down Route 101; dear America, something’s wrong), I saw something really alarming.
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>What happened was, I was speaking at a conference, sharing the stage with the Chairman of the SEC (by video) and (in the flesh) the SEC’s CIO and the FDIC’s Deputy CIO. No pointers because it deserves serious coverage. For the occasion, I (obviously) wore my best custom-made Italian suit (grey) and an understated-but-strong tie (mostly blue), along with my dapper new 
                    <a href="http://www.baileyhats.com/">Bailey’s</a> fedora. Then I took off for two heavy-geek meetings at Sun campuses and a visit to Technorati. When I pulled into the Sun parking lot, I thought about pulling the tie off and the jeans on but decided it would do ’em good to see a geek in a suit, and I have to say I got as many blank-faced 
                    <em>WTF-is-this</em> looks as anyone could want. But then, at the end of all my meetings, while I was trudging down a 
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/South_of_Market_%28San_Francisco%29">SoMa</a> street to my alarmingly-huge Avis van ($20 in gas for a day going up &amp; down Route 101; dear America, something’s wrong), I saw something really alarming.
                </p>
                <img src="IMG_4317.png" alt="Puzzling evidence, SoMa in San Francisco"/>
                <p>I stood there taking a bunch of pictures of these guys loading the truck and suddenly they noticed me and got real tense, so I left.</p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/18/Photocasting-Problems">
        <title>Photo RSS, Sort Of</title>
        <link href="Photocasting-Problems"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/18/Photocasting-Problems</id>
        <published>2006-01-18T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-18T22:11:24-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology/Syndication"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Syndication"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>Apple’s latest software bundle wraps RSS together with photo-publishing and they call it “Photocasting”. Reasonable enough. 
                    <a href="http://scripting.wordpress.com/2006/01/11/welcome-to-the-wonderful-wacky-world-of-apple-rss/">Dave Winer</a> and 
                    <a href="http://www.sitepoint.com/blogs/2006/01/17/apple-photocasting-mac-only-uses-invalid-rss/">Kevin Yank</a> have pointed out that there are some real problems with the RSS. So Mark Pilgrim did a deep-dive and it’s not just bad, it’s 
                    <a href="http://lists.apple.com/archives/syndication-dev/2006/Jan/msg00020.html">spectacularly bad</a>. To quote Mark: 
                    <i>To sum up, the “photocasting” feature centers around a single undocumented extension element in a namespace that doesn’t need to be declared. iPhoto 6 doesn’t understand the first thing about HTTP, the first thing about XML, or the first thing about RSS. It ignores features of HTTP that Netscape 4 supported in 1996, and mis-implements features of XML that Microsoft got right in 1997. It ignores 95% of RSS and Atom and gets most of the remaining 5% wrong.</i> This is really hard to understand. 
                    <i>[Update: The mob howling at Apple may have been a bit over-excited; check out Sam Ruby’s 
                        <a href="http://www.intertwingly.net/blog/2006/01/18/Photocasting-Hyperbole">careful and balanced</a> look at the situation, including the follow-up comments. And I apologize for leaping to conclusions; those with painful knowledge of the history of syndication politics will perhaps understand why, when the people listed at the top of this entry are all saying the same thing, one might assume that it’s probably true.]
                    </i>
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/16/Open-Source-Community">
        <title>Open-Source Whatever</title>
        <link href="Open-Source-Community"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/16/Open-Source-Community</id>
        <published>2006-01-16T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-16T23:19:05-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Business/Open Source"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Business"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Open Source"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World/Life Online/People"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Life Online"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="People"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>Over at O’Reilly, John Mark Walker writes 
                    <a href="http://www.onlamp.com/pub/a/onlamp/2006/01/12/no_oss_community.html?page=1">There Is No Open Source Community</a>, and Nicholas Carr, who enjoys decrying, well, anything popular, chimes in with 
                    <a href="http://www.roughtype.com/archives/2006/01/the_amorality_o_1.php">The Amorality of Open Source</a>. They both paint a picture of misguided innocents who believe in some starry-eyed vision of post-capitalist intellectual collectivism, but are actually pawns in the hands of larger economic forces. They’re both really wrong. Granted: Open Source is 
                    <em>not</em> a nation or a corporation or a political party or a religion. (While there are “movement people”, organized into the skeptical-of-each-other Open Source and Free Software sects, they are a tiny—albeit noisy—minority.) Absent those things, what is left? A collection of people who like working on software and look for opportunities, preferably but not necessarily paid, to do so. If that isn’t a “community”, what is? And furthermore, I would recommend that Walker and Carr spend some time hanging out in the IRC channels and pizza parties and conferences and mailing lists and wikis where the Open-Source people actually, you know, are. They would discover, now what’s the word I’m looking for... people who actively seek out their own kind, who share jargon and jokes and tools and thought leaders and enemies. The word I’m looking for is “community”. And anyone who thinks that this community would go away if Sun and IBM and Novell and so on were to stop funding it is nuts. Open Source Software is its own reward; that, and hanging out with people who share our passions. We don’ need no steenkin’ economics. Or ideologies either.
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/15/Football-Sunshine-Sex">
        <title>Football, Beans, Sunshine, Sex</title>
        <link href="Football-Sunshine-Sex"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/15/Football-Sunshine-Sex</id>
        <published>2006-01-15T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-15T20:58:54-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts/Photos"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Photos"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Sports/Football"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Sports"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Football"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World/Places/Vancouver"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="The World"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Places"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Vancouver"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">What happened was, we had some friends over for the Sunday football games, and the day turned out very pleasantly in a bunch of ways; herewith an illustrated narrative.</div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>What happened was, we had some friends over for the Sunday football games, and the day turned out very pleasantly in a bunch of ways; herewith an illustrated narrative.</p>
                <h2 id="p-1">Football</h2>
                <p>Oh my goodness gracious, that Indy-Steelers game was something. It turned out that our party was solidly packed with Pittsburgh fans and, despite the wildly-randomized happenstances of the last five minutes, they won the game fair and square. For my money, the defining play was the Colts’ late fourth-down gamble; they knew the rush was coming and had to be prepared for it and they still got slaughtered. It looked to me like three of them were blocking Polamalu; when Manning went down there were like five white shirts around him. If Indy can’t handle that Steelers defensive front, who can?</p>
                <p>Give the Steelers credit too for thinking; for coming out with an all-aerial attack featuring repeated strikes to that eight-foot-tall rookie tight end whom I’d never heard of and whose name I’ve already forgotten. The Colts’ surprise lasted long enough to give Pittsburgh a fourteen-point head start, which turned out to be (barely) enough.</p>
                <p>And like Roethlisberger said after the game, Bettis doesn’t fumble much and he doesn’t tackle much, but that desperation ankle-grab won’t be forgotten soon. Jerome better send him flowers.</p>
                <h2 id="p-2">Beans</h2>
                <p>I got up and started doing lunch prep sometime in the last quarter, but then had to put it on hold to catch the denouement. Even so, it was fine; to complement Lauren’s signature beef stew I tried making Malaysian-style Sambhal green beans, and they came out great. A little bit of work: you chop ’em and boil ’em and dry ’em and stir-fry ’em at the last minute with some shallots and garlic, then glaze ’em with oyster and fish and chili sauce plus a bit of cornstarch. Mmm, spicy and tasty.</p>
                <img src="IMGP2879.png" alt="Spring sunshine magnolia-branch shadows"/>
                <h2 id="p-4">Sunshine</h2>
                <p>Our quest for the 
                    <a href="/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/12/Rain">rain record</a> is still in effect but the sun came out and stayed out during the game, so after lunch I said “How about a walk” and we went for a lazy amble around the neighborhood. On the way down the front walk I got this year’s first picture of our much-photographed magnolia (above), just shadowbranches but there are lots of buds.
                </p>
                <p>Main Street in Vancouver is trying furiously to gentrify itself, but its grubby history is pushing back; here’s a house a block off Main that I bet is torn down in favor of chi-chi condos within five years.</p>
                <img src="IMGP2883.png" alt="Old house near Main Street in Vancouver"/>
                <h2 id="p-6">Sex</h2>
                <p>Well, there are signs of Spring, and we all know what young men’s fancy turns to thoughts of; and mine too. Even given that, I thought this stump remnant embedded in the grass was coming it a bit high; I suspect it’s due for censorship before too long.</p>
                <img src="IMGP2888.png" alt="Vaguely obscene stump embedded in grass"/>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/14/Naked-Conversations">
        <title>Naked Conversations</title>
        <link href="Naked-Conversations"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/14/Naked-Conversations</id>
        <published>2006-01-14T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-14T15:51:06-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology/Publishing"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Publishing"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Business/Blogging"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Business"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Blogging"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Subtitled 
                <i>How Blogs are Changing the Way Businesses Talk with Customers</i>, by Robert Scoble and Shel Israel. I got an advance copy of this a couple of months ago, with a note saying “Can we have a quote for the cover by Wednesday?” But I didn’t get around to reading it until several Wednesdays later. Summary: Lots of people will benefit from reading this; especially “Communications Professionals”. Most people who read 
                <span class="o">ongoing</span> won’t learn much, but they might enjoy it anyhow. Read on for more details.
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>Subtitled 
                    <i>How Blogs are Changing the Way Businesses Talk with Customers</i>, by Robert Scoble and Shel Israel. I got an advance copy of this a couple of months ago, with a note saying “Can we have a quote for the cover by Wednesday?” But I didn’t get around to reading it until several Wednesdays later. Summary: Lots of people will benefit from reading this; especially “Communications Professionals”. Most people who read 
                    <span class="o">ongoing</span> won’t learn much, but they might enjoy it anyhow. Read on for more details.
                </p>
                <img src="NC.png" class="inline" alt="Naked Conversations"/>
                <h2 id="p-1">Good Stuff</h2>
                <p>The best thing is that there’s little abstraction or theorizing; it’s all real stories about real people and their ventures into the blogosphere. They do draw some lessons, but never at too-great length, and it never reads like they’re lecturing.</p>
                <p>Another strong point is that there’s first-rate coverage of business blogging outside of North America. Granted, there isn’t very much of that happening yet, but some of the stories—in particular, the stories out of France—are rich with lessons that I think would apply anywhere. Some of those stories are 100% new to me and would be, I suspect, to most of my readers.</p>
                <p>Their conclusion is bold and one I agree with, although probably a little bit in advance of all the evidence being in: Blogging is good for good companies and bad for bad companies. Disclosure: I’m pretty sure that I didn’t invent that phrase, which doesn’t actually appear in 
                    <cite>Naked Conversations</cite>; I seem to recall reading it somewhere but can’t find the reference.
                </p>
                <p>My personal favorite fragment, unsurprisingly, is the one I appear in: 
                    <i>One competitor we know about, speaking off the record, told us “We had counted Sun out. We assumed by now they would be dead or irrelevant. They’re back. I think it’s their [expletive deleted] blogs. We just went into a customer meeting and they were asking us about some stuff that Tim Bray had posted that morning.”</i> So far, Scoble has politely ignored my whining, begging, pleading, and offers of huge bribes to find out who the competitor is. Hmm... I wonder if Maryam can be subverted?
                </p>
                <p>Another really good thing is that while 
                    <cite>Naked Conversations</cite> unabashedly sings the virtues of blogging, it tries hard to avoid being sucked into uncritical boosterism, pointing specifically at cases where what seemed like a horde of bloggers turned out to be just a few people in an echo chamber.
                </p>
                <h2 id="p-2">Problems</h2>
                <p>I don’t know how big a problem this will be for readers in general, but it bothered me a lot that while Rob and Shel obviously worked together to build the book, Shel wrote it. Which means it totally isn’t in Rob’s earnest high-velocity style, but rather a cool, neutral tone with lots of commas and subordinate clauses. I’m a big fan of Rob’s writing but, given that this book is aimed at people who still need to be convinced about blogging, maybe combining the medium and the message would have been asking too much of the reader. And to be fair, Scoble does have a day job.</p>
                <p>I was also irritated by occasional lapses into Microsoft-party-line-ism, for example: 
                    <i>Corporate customers have long understood that in enterprise environments freeware is often expensive to use because of the problems it can cause.</i> It would be nice for Redmond if that were true.
                </p>
                <p>Oh, and a quibble. They say: 
                    <i>...in 1988 a couple of Stanford kids came up with Google, which dramatically improved search results by employing intelligent algorithms rather than simple keywords...</i>. Oh, please; all search has been based on dumb algorithms since day one, and so is Google’s; their mojo is based on link-count-based relevance ranking, an idea they were the first to apply, combined with a really user-friendly UI (i.e., less is more) and outstanding operational skills (i.e. it’s fast and reliable).
                </p>
                <p>Finally, I kind of wish that Rob and Shel had written a book, not about business blogging, but about blogging’s wider cultural and societal impacts. This is, at the end of the day, a good book about business blogging. But really, I think the most interesting parts of this great big complicated global Naked Conversation have nothing to do with business.</p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/14/On-Intel">
        <title>On Intel</title>
        <link href="On-Intel"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/14/On-Intel</id>
        <published>2006-01-14T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-14T09:28:13-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Business/Marketing"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Business"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Marketing"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Technology"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>I was reading the big 
                    <cite>Business Week</cite> story on Intel, and it quoted CEO Paul Otellini: “He lays particular emphasis on marketing expertise because he thinks the only way Intel can succeed in new markets is by communicating more clearly what the technology can do for customers. ‘To sell technology now, you have to do it in a way where it’s much more simple,’ says Otellini. ‘You can’t talk about the bits and the bytes.’” This seems deeply wrong to me on a whole bunch of levels. People already know what computers and game consoles and telephones and all the other things with CPUs in them can do for them, and if they don’t, it’s not Intel’s job to explain, that belongs to the people who build the boxes that the consumers slap down their plastic for. Once the buyers understand, they care mostly about price, except for bleeding-edge gamers and other CPU hogs, who perforce 
                    <em>do</em> care about bits and bytes. Intel’s real customers are Apple and Intel and Dell and HP and IBM, and I guarantee those guys care about bits and bytes (and wattage), and even more about dollars per unit. So it looks to me like Intel’s charging off in the wrong direction with Viiv and Core and so on. Having said that, I suspect the Intel engineering tribe is maniacally focused on catching and beating AMD, and I wouldn’t want to bet against them in the long term; so they’ll probably do OK.
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/13/FSS">
        <title>FSS: Roads</title>
        <link href="FSS"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/13/FSS</id>
        <published>2006-01-13T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-14T09:27:28-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts/Photos"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Photos"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Friday Slide Scan #18 is from my 
                <a href="http://www.textuality.com/BillBray/">Dad’s</a> “Roads” category; three pictures spanning three countries, two continents, and two decades.
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>Friday Slide Scan #18 is from my 
                    <a href="http://www.textuality.com/BillBray/">Dad’s</a> “Roads” category; three pictures spanning three countries, two continents, and two decades.
                </p>
                <p>Below is the trading post in Meander River, not far from 
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High_Level">High Level, Alberta</a>; my parents and friends passed through on a vacation drive north to 
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Slave_Lake">Great Slave Lake</a> from 
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fort_Vermilion">Fort Vermilion</a> on vacation in the summer of 1956.
                </p>
                <img src="A9006.png" alt="Meander River, Alberta, trading post, 1956"/>
                <p>Next is the Baldock Freeway between Eugene and Tigard, Oregon, a precursor of I-5, sometime in the late fifties. I still have a vague memory of that old Chevy; I lounged in the capacious back seat 
                    <i>sans</i> seatbelts.
                </p>
                <img src="A9009.png" alt="Baldock Freeway, Oregon, late fifties"/>
                <p>Finally, an April 1964 shot from near the top of the Western slope of the pass over 
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Lebanon">Mount Lebanon</a> from Beirut to the Beka’a valley, looking back at the sun on the Mediterranean.
                </p>
                <img src="A9010.png" alt="Pass over the Lebanon range, 1964"/>
                <p>Images in the Friday Slide Scans are from 35mm slides taken between 1953 and 2003 by (in rough chronological order) 
                    <a href="http://www.textuality.com/BillBray/">Bill Bray</a>, 
                    <a href="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2004/08/11/MomsGarden">Jean Bray</a>, Tim Bray, Cath Bray, and 
                    <a href="http://www.laurenwood.org/anyway/">Lauren Wood</a>; when I know exactly who took one, I’ll say; in this case, Bill and/or Jean Bray. Most but not all of the slides were on Kodachrome; they were digitized using a Nikon CoolScan 4000 ED scanner and cleaned up by a combination of the Nikon scanning software and PhotoShop Elements.
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry xml:base="When/200x/2006/01/12/Rain">
        <title>Rain and Silence and Reggaetón</title>
        <link href="Rain"/>
        <id>http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2006/01/12/Rain</id>
        <published>2006-01-12T12:00:00-08:00</published>
        <updated>2006-01-12T17:53:36-08:00</updated>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts/Music"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Arts"/>
        <category scheme="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/What/" term="Music"/>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>If it lasts through Sunday, Vancouver (and Seattle just down the road) will break a 1953 record for continuous rainy days. Recently there’s not much rattling around inside asking to be written and I partly blame all those clouds and, weirdly, the fact that it’s been weeks since I saw anything that I wanted to take a picture of. I have this great big queue of interesting Web stuff to write about, but you know, if I don’t someone else will and if they don’t it probably didn’t need writing. The Web’s like that. But today I was driving up 101 heading for SFO and didn’t like what KFOG was playing and hit Seek and listened to half an hour of 
                    <a href="http://www.univision.com/content/channel.jhtml?chid=9598&amp;schid=9793">La Kalle</a> which plays 
                    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reggaeton">Reggaetón</a>, and the DJs veer back and forth between Spanish and English three times in the average hyperenthusiastic sentence. The music’s complicatedly trying to be Latino-sentimental and hip-hop-tough and reggae-happy all at once, which leaves gaps it occasionally falls into, but more of it is good than bad, and a couple of times it had me hoppin’ back and forth on my butt in the driver’s seat. When I stopped to gas up the rental the song they were playing was too good to turn off so I cranked that sucker and entertained the whole gas station while I did my bit for the Saudi economy. A young dude in a good blue suit and haircut gassing 
                    <em>his</em> rental raised an eyebrow at the grey-bearded gringo honkey gettin’ down. As if I cared.
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
