<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- $Id: related.xml,v 1.9 2005/11/09 19:35:14 hoschek3 Exp $          -->
<document>
	<properties>
		<author email="whoschek.AT.lbl.DOT.gov">Wolfgang Hoschek</author>
		<title>Frequently Asked Questions / Related Information</title>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<!-- ##################################################################################### -->
<section name="Frequently Asked Questions">
<ul>
	<li><i>How does Nux relate to Saxon?</i>
		<p>
		Nux wraps Saxon via a XOM-friendly API, hiding most of Saxon's substantial complexity and 
		making it accessible via a convenient, powerful and efficient API.
		In general, Saxon (and by its virtue, Nux) implements the latest and greatest XQuery specs.
		Nux supports XQuery in the same way that Saxon does. 
		If Saxon supports XQuery feature XYZ, then Nux automatically inherits that feature as well, 
		with the very same semantics.
		For example, Saxon and Nux implement XQuery's <i>full axis feature</i>, 
		i.e., support all 12 XPath axes (except the namespace axis which has been deprecated by the W3C).
		In particular, anything that can be done with the Saxon API can be done with the Nux API.
		Like Saxon-B, Nux XQuery is not schema aware, unlike the commercial Saxon SA version.
		Nux contributed its Saxon-XOM bridge back to the Saxon codebase.
		</p>
	</li>
		
	<li><i>What about support for database integration and the 
		<a href="http://www.jcp.org/en/jsr/detail?id=225">XQJ</a> standard?</i>
		<p>
		XQJ will be very useful, but it is still immature, in flux and mostly without real implementations. Once XQJ stabilizes, and implementations of it become available, 
		we will also support plugging in any XQJ implementation via a factory interface.
		But that day doesn't seem close yet.
		</p>
	</li>
	
	<li><i>Where does the project name stem from?</i> 
		<p>
		No, it's not an akronym. 
		For anthropologists: The Goddess <i>Nux</i> (Night) was one of the four original primeval Greek deities, 
		who were the first entities to be formed out of Chaos, her siblings being 
		Eros (Love), Gaea (Earth) and Erebos (Darkness). 
		<i>Nux vomica</i> also refers to a tree native to the East Indies, as well as its nut-like seeds. 
		In homeopathy, it is one of the most commonly prescribed remedies.
		</p>				
	</li>
				
	<li><i>I'd like to help. How can I contribute?</i>
		<p>
		Your contributions are most welcome, be they suggestions for improvement, 
		problem reports, bug fixes, patches, or anything else. 
		In particular, a comprehensive suite of JUnit test cases in your area of interest 
		would be a very useful addition.
		</p>
	</li>
		
</ul>
</section>


		<!-- ##################################################################################### -->
<section name="Related Information">

<p>
A GUI XQuery Editor helps to learn the query language, and to quickly try out 
queries during early development stages. Such editors include
<a target="_blank" href="http://www.oxygenxml.com">Oxygen</a> 
(commercial but with free trial, including Eclipse plugin)
and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.stylusstudio.com/xquery_editor.html">Stylus Studio</a> 
(commercial but with free trial). 
Using such rapid prototyping GUIs before deploying into your Nux-based production 
application can speed up development and early testing.
Incidentally, these GUIs also use the Saxon XQuery engine internally, just like Nux.
</p>
<p>
Easy-to-read tutorials and other material about XQuery include:
<ul>
   <li><a href="http://www.stylusstudio.com/xquery_primer.html">Learning XQuery in 10 Minutes</a></li>
   <li><a href="http://www.stylusstudio.com/xquery_flwor.html">Introduction to the XQuery FLWOR Expression</a></li>
   <li><a href="http://www.w3schools.com/xpath/">XPath Tutorial</a></li>
   <li><a href="http://www.yukonxml.com/articles/xquery/">Essential XQuery</a></li>
   <li><a href="http://www.datadirect.com/news/whatsnew/xquerybook.asp">XQuery - A Guided Tour</a></li>
   <li><a href="http://www.informit.com/content/downloads/chap2_0321180607.pdf">Influences on the Design of XQuery</a></li>
   <li><a href="http://www.softwareag.com/xml/tools/xquery_primer.pdf">XQuery Primer</a></li>
   <!-- <li><a href="http://www.datypic.com/IntroductionToXQuery.pdf">Introduction to XQuery</a></li> -->
   <!-- <li><a href="http://www.informit.com/title/0672324792">XQuery Kick Start</a></li> -->
   <!-- <li><a href="http://cafeconleche.org/slides/xmlsig/xquery/XQuery.html">XQuery Tutorial 2</a></li> -->
   <li><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/xquery-use-cases/">W3C Sample XQueries</a> (also contained in the Saxon download).</li>
   <li><a href="http://www.xquery.com/">www.xquery.com</a></li>
   <li><a href="http://www.w3.org/XML/Query">W3C XQuery and XPath Specifications</a> (also with news, products, etc.)</li>
   <li><a href="http://idealliance.org/proceedings/xtech05/papers/02-03-01/">Comparing XSLT and XQuery</a></li>
   <li><a href="http://www.softwareag.com/trainingweek2003/presentations/XML_Query_Michael_Kay.ppt">XQuery 1.0 vs. XPath 1.0, XPath 2.0 and XSLT 2.0</a></li>
   <li><a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/qexo/XQ-Gen-XML.html">Generating XML and HTML using XQuery</a></li>
   <li><a href="http://idealliance.org/papers/dx_xmle04/papers/02-03-02/02-03-02.html">XSLT and XPath Optimization</a></li>
   <li><a href="http://www-128.ibm.com/developerworks/xml/library/x-xslt2/">Saxon: Anatomy of an XSLT processor</a></li>
</ul>
</p>
</section>

	</body>
</document>
